Guide to the Jeffrey Gerson Brooklyn politics research collection 2013.021
Brooklyn Historical Society
- William Thompson, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 29, Box 10, Cassette 29)
  This interview took place on May 16, 1988. The audio related to this interview includes Jeffrey Gerson's comments after the interview and summarizes what Thompson said after the interview. This interview has an accompanying transcript.
- Burton B. Turkus, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- United Action Democratic Association, 1944-1950 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- United Action Democratic Association annual dinner programs, 1947-1961 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- United Action Democratic Association annual dinner programs, 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- United Action Democratic Association annual dinner programs, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Unity Democratic Club, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Urban League, 1957-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Albert Vann, 1966-1993 (Box 6, Folder 4, Box 10, Cassette 30)
  Albert "Al" Vann was born on November 19, 1934 in Brooklyn. Vann graduated from Toledo University in 1959, then earned a master's degree in education from Yeshiva University and a master's degree in guidance counseling from Long Island University. He was a New York State Assemblyman representing the 56th Assembly District from 1975 to 2001.
  Vann married Mildred Cooke in 1967. They had four children and lived in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. Vann died on July 14, 2022.
  This interview took place on June 10, 1993. This interview does not have an accompanying transcript.
- Robert Wagner, 1957 - circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Robert Wagner, Jr., 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Alton R. Waldon, Jr., circa 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Ivan Warner, 1957-1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Weeksville, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Henry Claflin Wells, circa 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  This file contains a paper titled "Urban Political Development and the Power of Local Groups: A Case Study of Politics in South Brooklyn, 1865-1935" by Henry Claflin Wells.
- Henry Claflin Wells, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11 -12)
  This file contains a conference paper titled "Political Development in Urban America: The Case of the Brooklyn Machine" by Henry Claflin Wells.
- Jitu Weusi, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 13, Box 10, Cassette 31, Cassette 32, Cassette 33, Cassette 34)
  Jitu K. Weusi was born Leslie R. Campbell on October 25, 1939 in Brooklyn. His mother was active in the Democratic Party. Weusi was a member of the Congress on Racial Equality (CORE). After college, Weusi became a teacher in public junior high schools in New York City. He founded the African American Teachers Association along with other Black teachers (including Albert Vann) after the United Federation of Teachers (UFT) did not support the 1964 Citywide School Boycott.
  Weusi founded the Uhuru Sasa School, a Black independent private school for inner-city youth, and co-founded The East, a community education and arts organization in Bedford-Stuyvesant. Weusi was involved with the New York Chapter of the National Black United Front and African Americans United for Political Power, which worked to elect David Dinkins as New York City mayor. Weusi died in 2013.
  This interview took place on July 19, 1993. This interview does not have an accompanying transcript.
- Everett Williams, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Everett Williams was born on January 2, 1905 in Prince Edward County, Virginia. He moved to Brooklyn with his sister when he was a teenager for more opprtunities. Williams worked in shore repair at Abraham and Straus for 40 years. He was a member of Bertram Baker's United Action Club. Williams died in 2001.
  This interview took place on July 21, 1988. This interview does not have an accompanying transcript.
- Williamsburg, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Malcolm Wilson, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Basil Wilson and Charles Green, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  This file contains three papers titled "The State of Black Politics in New York City," "The Afro-American, Caribbean Dialectic: White Incumbents Black Constituents and the 1984 Election in New York City," and "The Black Church and the Struggle for Black Empowerment in New York City" by Basil Wilson and Charles Green.
- Mary E. Woods, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 18, Box 10, Cassette 35)
  Mary Elizabeth Woods was born on March, 21, 1930 in Manhattan. The family lived mostly in Greenwich Village. Woods graduated from Cornell University in 1951 and she spent four years in Binghamton, New York labor organizing for workers at the Endicott Johnson Corporation.
  She moved to Crown Heights in Brooklyn in 1957 and worked at the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children. She was active in the Unity Democratic Club. Woods died in 2005.
  The interview took place on November 13, 1989. This interview does not have an accompanying transcript.
- Samuel Wright, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Samuel "Sam" Daniel Wright was born on February 13, 1925 in the Ocean Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. Wright's father was active in the local Republican party. Wright graduated from Brooklyn Law School in 1960. He was elected to New York State Assembly in 1965 and was chairman of the Ocean Hill-Brownsville school district. In 1973, he was elected to the New York City Council, but lost his seat in 1978 when he was convicted for receiving payment from an educational materials producer in exchange for a guaranteed contract with the school board. Wright also ran against Shirley Chisholm for the 12th district congressional seat in 1976, but was unsuccessful. Wright died on January 20, 1998.
  This interview took place on March 22, 1989. This interview does not have an accompanying transcript.
- Edward A. Wynne, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Lila Yagerman, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21, Box 7, Folder 1-3, Box 10, Cassette 36, Cassette 37, Cassette 38, Cassette 39)
  Lila Yagerman was born on October 22, 1928 in Brooklyn. She lived in the Marine Park/Sheepshead Bay area from 1954 until at least the time of this interview in 1987. She graduated from Jefferson High School in Brownsville in 1945. Lila Yagerman was active in Brooklyn clubhouse politics and was co-leader of the 21st Assembly District. Yagerman died in 1997. Her son created a scholarship in her name at Cardozo Law School in Manhattan.
  This interview took place on July 13, 1987 at Lila Yagerman's home in Brooklyn. Audio related to this interview also includes Jeffrey Gerson's comments after the interview. This interview has an accompanying transcript.
- Sharon Zukin / Gilda Zwerman, circa 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  This file contains a paper by Sharon Zukin and Gilda Zwerman titled "Reprivatizing the Ghetto: Investment, Employment, and Race in the Postwar Transformations of Brownsville."